<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>
   Title
  </title>
  <link>
   https://your-website.com
  </link>
  <description>
   Your feed description
  </description>
  <language>
   en-us
  </language>
  <item>
   <title>
    Vital That Coffee Industry Adapts to Climate Change, Illy Chairman Says
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/vital-that-coffee-industry-adapts-to-climate-change-illy-chairman-says-40daff6b
   </link>
   <content>
    Coffee producers have to adapt to climate change in order for global prices to stabilize, said Andrea Illy, chairman of Illycaffè and third generation heir of the Italian company’s dynasty. 
Coffee prices have reached record highs this year, and are unlikely to retreat any time soon as poor weather conditions in the world’s main growing regions—Vietnam and Brazil—squeeze global production. The price of arabica futures has risen nearly 70% over the past year, while robusta coffee futures have more than doubled. 
Efforts to curb climate change include the European Union’s Deforestation Regulation—or EUDR—which aims to guarantee that consumer products don’t contribute to deforestation. The regulation was supposed to come into force by the end of the year, but the EU Commission proposed a one-year delay amid pressure from industries and governments. 
Illy talked about the effects of climate change on coffee prices and the challenges the sector is facing. The following has been edited for length and clarity. 
Q: What factors are driving coffee prices at the moment? 
Climate change is heavily impacting coffee agriculture. Coffee grows in a very narrow climatic band, both in terms of temperature and moisture, and requires a circular, regular pattern. Climate change is giving us the exact opposite of regular climate conditions. The evil in the room is the so-called “ENSO cycle,” which is the alternation of the El Nino and the La Nina. El Nino causes heat waves with extreme drought, while La Nina is excessive rain and cold weather. What is increasing is the peak heat of El Nino. 
Latin America, where two-thirds of coffee is grown, is the most impacted region. In Brazil, the effect of climate change is amplified as a result of the deforestation of the Atlantic Forest around a century ago. So we have twice as high global warming in the Minas Gerais regions where coffee is grown compared to other places in the world. 
It’s unpredictable… we weren’t expecting such a mess this year. Extreme weather in Brazil and extreme drought in Vietnam triggered a rally in prices, which we didn’t foresee. With these weather patterns, we can expect lower output in the years to come, which is the perfect trigger for market speculation. The situation is getting more and more volatile. 
Q: What conditions do we need for prices to normalize? 
In the immediate term, we need rain in Brazil, and the price will fall immediately. But in the long term, we need countries to adapt to climate change. Brazil is an exception, as it’s the most competitive coffee-producing country with around 40% of global output and a substantial number of growers with good financing terms from the state. So Brazil can invest in adaptation, but most of the rest of the world is made up of small holders. 
There are more or less 12 million hectares cultivated with coffee around the world, and around 12 and a half million growers. The average grower cultivates far below one hectare. How could they grow larger, or invest in adapting to climate change, if they are receiving just 5% of the wholesale value of [a cup of] coffee? There is absolutely not enough in terms of cash flow and margins to reinvest part of your income in adaptation. Price volatility makes it even more difficult. So we need improving economic practices. 
What’s also needed is the renewal of plantations. In Brazil, they substitute plants every 12 to 15 years. In some countries, there are plants which are 80 years to a century old. You can guess how little productivity they have and how little resilience they have against pathogens or any kind of adverse factors. So what we have been advocating for many years is to create the conditions for consuming countries to invest in those plantations… even through a public-private fund. 
Q: Has the company been able to absorb the cost increases itself? 
We try to strike a balance. We try to absorb costs temporarily. Of course, from time to time we have windows where we adjust our pricing, but in general, we don’t adjust our pricing to cover temporary market cost increases. It’s a kind of an acrobatic gym exercise every time, but it’s something we’re starting to get used to. 
Q: What are the main challenges that the EU deforestation law poses to the industry? Has Illy taken any steps to prepare for when this regulation comes into force? 
The EUDR is motivated by good intentions. We have to stop deforesting for agriculture… But in the timeframe considered by the regulation, coffee didn’t undergo substantial deforestation. 
We pioneer direct sourcing and we have a team of agronomists checking that there’s no deforestation or unsustainable labor conditions. We now have traceability for each and every coffee plantation, each and every coffee lot, each and every coffee bean. So we did prepare ourselves for any possible consequences [of the EUDR], including replacing some components of our blends with some from other countries. But imagine a company that buys through traders, and traders buy through cooperatives… you completely lose traceability. 
The concern is more for the weakest part of the coffee chain, which are coffee growers in producing countries, particularly the less fortunate ones. Take for example Ethiopia. 40% of the coffee grown in Ethiopia is exported to Europe, which is by far the largest consuming region. Should they not be in the capacity to export to Europe any longer, they could redirect some of the coffee to other countries like the U.S. or in Asia, but not 40%. You would have 20% of people left jobless and forced to leave their land, which translates into a potential humanitarian crisis. 
Q: What would you like the EU to change or amend when it comes to this regulation? 
To simplify the procedure. For instance, a mechanism that requires producers to ensure that a coffee region or plantation is deforestation free. Some kind of self-certification mechanism. And also to give time to adjust. If you have deforested land, you can set a road map for restoring what has been deforested, with some time and some funds. There also needs to be more of a carrot and stick approach to companies, rather than just the stick. [The EU] helps you improve your sustainability with targets and regulation. Then if you don’t comply, you get punished. This would be ideal, because it could also create some complicity. 
Advertisement 
Write to Giulia Petroni at giulia.petroni@wsj.com and Joseph Hoppe at joseph.hoppe@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Natural Gas Climbs Closer to $3/mbtu Mark
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/natural-gas-higher-as-temperatures-slowly-back-down-28b4d1e4
   </link>
   <content>
    1624 ET – Natural gas futures finish up 2.9% to $2.97 per million Btu, snapping a two-session losing streak, with weather forecasts seen as gradually growing colder on the East Coast. This brings natural gas closer to the 2024 high of $3.313 reached in mid-January. How the weather fares is ultimately the main drivers for futures, says NatGasWeather.com in a note. “We continue to expect gradually colder weather systems will arrive into the northern U.S. for the 2nd half of October, with highs of 40s-50s,” says the firm. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais) 
Front Month Nymex Natural Gas for Nov. delivery gained 8.40 cents per million British thermal units, or 2.91% to $2.9700 per million British thermal units today 
—Largest one day dollar and percentage gain since Friday, Sept. 27, 2024 
—Snaps a two session losing streak 
—Highest settlement value since Wednesday, June 12, 2024 
—Off 16.92% from its 52-week high of $3.575 hit Tuesday, Oct. 31, 2023 
—Up 88.57% from its 52-week low of $1.575 hit Tuesday, March 26, 2024 
—Down 6.19% from 52 weeks ago 
—Off 10.35% from its 2024 settlement high of $3.313 hit Friday, Jan. 12, 2024 
—Up 88.57% from its 2024 settlement low of $1.575 hit Tuesday, March 26, 2024 
—Off 80.69% from its record high of $15.378 hit Tuesday, Dec. 13, 2005 
—Year-to-date it is up 45.60 cents or 18.14% 
All prices are calculated based on the settlement price of the current front month contract. 
Source: Dow Jones Market Data 
1051 ET – Inventories of natural gas rose by 55 billion cubic feet (Bcf) for the week ended Sept. 27, the EIA reports Thursday. That’s slightly less than forecast by analysts surveyed by The Wall Street Journal this week, who estimated stocks to rise by 58 Bcf. Total supply rise to 3,547 Bcf, which nearly 4% higher that this time a year ago and close to 6% higher than the five-year average. Natural gas futures are up 2.2%, with the EIA storage figure seen as a bullish for prices versus the typical rate of injections for this time of year — which last year was around 98 Bcf, BOK Financial says in a note. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais) 
Advertisement 
0942 ET – Average temperatures in the U.S. have been higher than normal for this time of year, says EBW Analytics Group, citing data from DTN. However, these higher-than-normal temperatures are slowly pulling back, and are expected to be mostly at normal levels for this time of year on the East Coast by the middle of October. Temperatures will remain above-average further west, according to DTN projections, but by less of a margin than seen currently. Traders will also be watching for the EIA’s storage report to confirm the size of the current surplus of natural gas being stored in the U.S., with Hurricane Helene not expected to significantly derail current trends. Most-active natural gas futures are up 2.4%. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Natural Gas Climbs 12% for Quarter
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/natural-gas-rises-on-west-coast-heat-storm-watches-1b5754ad
   </link>
   <content>
    1559 ET – Front-month natural gas futures rise 12.4% to $2.923 per million British thermal units in the 3Q — making it 65.8% natural gas has risen in the past two quarters, and 37.4% this past month they’ve risen. Ritterbusch and Associates in a note says that fundamentals are seen as exhausted for natural gas, but issues stemming from Hurricane Helene and potential issues coming from the 3 tropical systems active in the Atlantic Ocean provided support. “Any supply disruption that could accelerate the expected further narrowing in the storage surplus will likely receive an exaggerated response,” says the firm. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais) 
Advertisement 
1100 ET – Natural gas is up 0.5% with heat in the West expected to drive up demand for air conditioning. “Forecasted heat wave in the west is being countered by cooler temps in the east,” BOK Financial says in a note. “Throw in another Tropical Storm in the Gulf that could reach Hurricane force and an erratic nervous trade in Nat Gas is the result.” According to the NOAA’s National Hurricane Center, there are three tropical systems active in the Atlantic Ocean as of today — two being tropical storms and one being a tropical depression. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Natural Gas Falls Back
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/europes-gas-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns-7be80d0b
   </link>
   <content>
    15:49 ET – Natural gas futures finished the day lower, falling 0.4% to $2.886 per million British thermal units. It’s the second-straight decline for natural gas, and makes it 1.3% natural gas has fallen in those sessions. Futures hit a wall in Wednesday’s session, says Ritterbusch and Associates in a note. “The subsequent selloff suggests near term price consolidation unless tomorrow’s EIA storage posts a bullish surprise,” says the firm. The firm eyes the possibility of a cold November cutting into a natural gas supply surplus significantly, which Thursday’s report could set the stage for. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais) 
1034 ET – The tight balance of supply and demand in natural gas is continuing to support higher prices, which has traders shrugging off warm temperatures in much of the U.S. that typically add pressure this time of year. Anticipation is more surrounding how U.S. weather may look in December, says NatGasWeather.com in a note. “If December were to play out colder than normal, surpluses would flip to deficit,” says the firm — qualifying this statement by adding that Decembers in the U.S. have been warmer than average for several consecutive years. Natural gas futures are up 2.7% in morning trading. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais) 
Advertisement 
0751 GMT – European natural-gas prices rise in early trade, boosted by fears that escalating tensions in the Middle East could hit key supply routes in the region. Focus is now on Israel’s response to Iran’s missile attacks overnight, with concerns of an all-out war potentially threatening gas fields offshore Israel, which supply southern neighbors Egypt and Jordan. Meanwhile in Ukraine, fears of supply disruptions are still high after President Volodymyr Zelensky said the past week that an intelligence report indicates Russia is planning strikes on nuclear facilities. Benchmark Dutch TTF trades 0.5% higher at 39.46 euros a megawatt hour. (giulia.petroni@wsj.com)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Natural Gas Tumbles to Close Week
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/natural-gas-backs-away-from-3-mmbtu-mark-6e5f3b43
   </link>
   <content>
    1545 ET – Natural gas futures settle down 3.9% to $2.854 per mmBtu after nearing the $3 mark yesterday. Temperatures in the U.S. remain higher than normal for most of the country, according to a weather forecast from agricultural research firm DTN. Meanwhile, natural gas rigs in the U.S. increased by three, according to weekly data from Baker Hughes. Natural gas prices have been having difficulty breaking the $3 per mmBtu level, experiencing ‘psychological’ resistance at that level, according to EBW Analytics Group in a note. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais) 
Advertisement 
1049 ET – Natural gas futures are down 3.3% in morning trade, backing further away from the $3 per mmBtu mark that the most-active contract neared in the Thursday session. Some analysts speculate that natural gas is in a position to cross that level soon, with Ritterbusch and Associates speculating that the price will exceed $3 within the next two weeks. “Overall balances appear to be improving gradually as the dynamic of surplus contraction remains much intact with another sizable reduction in the supply overhang expected in next week’s EIA [report],” says the firm in a note. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Slide in Iron Ore Prices a Hiccup for Miners Amid Copper Scramble
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/slide-in-iron-ore-prices-a-hiccup-for-miners-amid-copper-scramble-3f629b52
   </link>
   <content>
    The price of iron ore has dropped to its lowest in nearly two years, a drain on profits for some of the world’s biggest miners as they raise bets on commodities like copper that they expect will be essential to the energy transition. 
Iron ore, used to make steel, is one of the worst-performing mined commodities this year, hit hard by the crisis in China’s property market as far fewer homes start construction. 
The benchmark price for iron ore is down by as much as 36% in 2024 so far. A daily price of $90.25 a metric ton on Tuesday is the lowest one recorded since November 2022, according to S&amp;P Global Commodity Insights, which assesses iron-ore prices. The price edged a tad higher Wednesday. 
Several of the world’s biggest miners rely on the commodity for a big chunk of their profits. For BHP Group, the world’s most valuable miner, iron ore contributed 64% of earnings in the year through June. Rio Tinto, the second-biggest miner by value, relies on iron ore for nearly seven of every 10 dollars it earns. 
Those companies have much lower mining costs than smaller rivals, meaning their mammoth iron-ore operations continue to be lucrative even at reduced prices. They may not be as big a moneymaker in the future as they have been in the recent past, though. 
The downturn is a hit to corporate war chests at a time when miners, after years of holding back on big investments, are increasing spending on projects and acquisitions in copper and some other commodities, including lithium. Those commodities are expected to experience a sharp rise in demand as more money pours into renewable energy, electric vehicles and power grids. 
The mining industry needs to consistently finance and build new copper projects at a rate that was only achieved for a few years at the end of the China-led commodities boom if the world is to meet a goal of limiting the rise in temperatures to close to 1.5 degrees Celsius, commodities consulting firm Wood Mackenzie has previously said. 
Of the commodities that miners dig up, iron ore is one of the most vulnerable to a slowdown in China, which buys seven in every 10 tons of iron ore shipped globally. Its property sector is a top source of steel demand. 
Chinese housing data suggest that the sector remains in bad shape, despite the government stepping up support for it and other industries in recent months. As a result, many steel mills there are losing money on their sales. 
“China’s steel industry has raised alarm about how tough conditions can become,” said ING analyst Ewa Manthey. In August, steel giant China Baowu Steel Group cautioned that the situation facing the steel sector is more dire than prior downturns this century, and that the slump is likely to be longer and more difficult than previously expected. 
A 5% fall in China’s iron-ore imports in August from a year earlier is the first annual contraction since November 2022 and reflects the subdued state of steel demand in China, said Commonwealth Bank of Australia analyst Vivek Dhar. 
Iron ore has been piling up at the country’s ports, with stockpiles stored at major Chinese port facilities up by roughly 30% year to date. 
Analysts are divided over what could happen to prices next. 
Some reckon iron-ore prices are likely to remain under pressure, citing the losses at Chinese steel mills and buildup in port stockpiles. ING’s Manthey expects the price to average $95 in the final quarter of the year. 
Others argue mining costs should stop prices from falling much further and that the commodity could enjoy a bounce as iron-ore supply growth slows and steel mills restock raw materials following the summer, as they typically do. Commonwealth Bank’s Dhar forecasts iron ore will trade between $100 and $110 a ton in the fourth quarter. 
Economists at BHP last month said the market is experiencing a deepening glut and they expect supplies will continue to outpace demand into 2025. 
Still, they estimated mining costs could put a floor under prices somewhere in the range of $80 to $100 a ton. The thinking is that dips below that level would cause high-cost producers to stop mining, helping to rebalance supply and demand. 
BHP Chief Executive Mike Henry pointed to the company’s margins as reassurance the miner can ride out volatility in prices. The miner recorded a margin of 68% for its iron-ore business last fiscal year. 
Still, investors worry the big miners’ iron-ore businesses are so huge that there’s little they can do to counter a sharp fall in prices. 
“Right now, there’s real pain in [the] iron-ore world,” Panmure Liberum analyst Tom Price said in a note. On the near-term outlook, Price is in the bear camp. 
“Already down 30-40% YTD, is there any upside for ore prices? Not yet,” he said. 
Shares in BHP and Rio Tinto are down by roughly 20% year to date. Brazil’s Vale, another top producer, is down roughly 35%. 
Advertisement 
Write to Rhiannon Hoyle at rhiannon.hoyle@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    U.S. Natural Gas Futures Hold Their Ground
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/europes-gas-eases-on-ample-supplies-despite-middle-east-concerns-41c0aaa6
   </link>
   <content>
    1534 ET – U.S. natural gas futures settle modestly lower in rangebound trade with market focus on Hurricane Milton that’s expected to crash into the Florida Gulf coast on Wednesday as a major storm. “Hurricane Milton has become negative news for the natural gas space with the prospects of knocking out major areas of power demand throughout Florida,” Dennis Kissler of BOK Financial BOKF 2.70%increase; green up pointing triangle says in a note. In its monthly outlook, the EIA raised its 4Q spot price estimate for Henry Hub to $2.81/mmBtu from $2.52/mmBtu. The EIA expects natural gas prices to rise in 2025 as LNG exports increase by around 2 billion cubic feet a day and U.S. consumption remains flat around 89 Bcf/d. The Nymex front month settles down 0.5% at $2.733/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com) 
0925 ET – U.S. natural gas futures are holding near support around $2.70 with the market attentive as Hurricane Milton moves toward Florida. “A near-term trading range between about $2.70 and $3.00 is shaping up when looking across the next couple of weeks,” Ritterbusch says in a note. The hurricane could have some influence on both supply and demand, the firm adds, but notes that the impact on cooling demand from storms tends to be lower this late in the season. The Nymex front month is off 1.6% at $2.702/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com) 
Advertisement 
0802 GMT – European natural-gas prices fall in early European trade as weak demand and high inventories ease concerns over disruption risks in the Middle East. The benchmark Dutch TTF contract is down 1.3% at 39.71 euros a megawatt hour. According to industry group Gas Infrastructure Europe, EU storage levels are 94.56% full—well above the five-year average ahead of the upcoming heating season and at a time when gas demand is still subdued. Yet, TTF prices are up 9% on the month and almost 23% year to date on fears that further military escalation between Israel and Iran could impact Israel’s offshore gas fields supplying Jordan and Egypt or disrupt liquefied-natural-gas flows through the Strait of Hormuz. (giulia.petroni@wsj.com)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Why Washington and Big Oil Are Investing Billions in Ammonia
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/business/energy-oil/why-washington-and-big-oil-are-investing-billions-in-ammonia-eef4d2eb
   </link>
   <content>
    Most people think of ammonia as a household cleaner. To big oil companies, climate investors and the U.S. government, it is a hot commodity that is attracting billions of dollars for its use in fertilizer and low-carbon energy.  
The latest bet is a $1.56 billion Energy Department loan commitment for an ammonia project in Indiana. The agreement comes on top of a recent $2.35 billion deal for a Gulf Coast project by an Australia-based energy company, a big investment from Abu Dhabi’s national oil company in an Exxon Mobil XOM 0.38%increase; green up pointing triangle project in Texas and a large effort in Mississippi from ammonia giant CF Industries CF -0.52%decrease; red down pointing triangle. 
Ammonia, which is a mixture of hydrogen and nitrogen, has long been a critical ingredient in fertilizer, but it is also a big emitter of greenhouse gases because it is typically made using fossil fuels. Projects like the one in Indiana are considered low-carbon because they trap the CO2 emissions from the process and bury them underground.  
Ammonia doesn’t produce carbon emissions when burned as fuel, driving a new wave of activity from companies angling to ship it all over the world. Increasing domestic supply is a priority after Russia’s invasion of Ukraine in 2022 roiled the market and pushed up prices. Russia is one of the world’s biggest producers.  
“It’s important for us to have a diverse supply chain and make sure we’re not dependent on other countries for this really important chemical,” Jigar Shah, head of the Energy Department’s Loan Programs Office, said in an interview. The program is rushing to get deals done before the election.  
The office has agreed to a deal with Wabash Valley Resources, a producer backed by oil companies and hydrogen-vehicle startup Nikola NKLA -1.15%decrease; red down pointing triangle. The company aims to repurpose a facility that was part of a decades-old coal plant in Indiana for low-carbon ammonia production. 
Founded in 2016, Wabash uses a byproduct of oil refining to make ammonia and says it has an advantage over competitors because its facility is close to the farms where fertilizer will be used to grow corn. It expects to produce 500,000 metric tons of ammonia a year.  
The deal also adds to recent investments in carbon capture, which has a poor track record but got billions of dollars in tax credits from the 2022 climate law. Projects such as Wabash’s are seen as more practical because they use a proven process to trap a nearly pure stream of CO2.   
Once it starts operating in 2027, Wabash expects to get about $140 million in carbon sequestration tax credits annually on top of the loan. The company’s project previously got government grants for studying carbon storage options near its plant in West Terre Haute, Ind., which set the table for Environmental Protection Agency approval of storage wells. 
Wabash still needs to raise about $800 million in equity and meet other project milestones before it starts receiving the loan. Daniel Williams, chief operating officer, said the company has about 75% of that equity funding in place and is talking to corporate partners.   
Another low-carbon ammonia producer, Nebraska startup Monolith, received a $1 billion commitment from the loan office in 2021 but still hasn’t received the funds.  
On the Gulf Coast, Australia-based Woodside Energy WDS -2.05%decrease; red down pointing triangle recently paid $2.35 billion for a plant in Beaumont, Texas, where it plans to make low-carbon ammonia. A nearby Exxon low-carbon ammonia project has a deal with Abu Dhabi’s national oil company and is in talks for additional cash from Japanese conglomerate Mitsubishi 8058 -0.08%decrease; red down pointing triangle. 
Advertisement 
Exxon is also working with CF Industries on its carbon-capture effort in Mississippi and a similar project in Louisiana as part of its push into carbon management.   
Subsidies are critical for the projects because rising costs are derailing many climate efforts, fueling a series of bankruptcies in recent months. Williams said Wabash’s equipment and project costs have risen about 25% to 50% in the past three years. Cost setbacks have hurt many projects involving only hydrogen, which is difficult to store and transport.  
Wabash still needs to build the transportation infrastructure to carry the carbon several miles to storage sites, a process that has angered opponents of the development. Williams said the ammonia will have as much as 80% lower emissions than traditional ammonia and that the government support shows the project is worthy of development. The EPA received more than 1,000 public comments during its storage permit review. 
The deal is the loan program’s first involving carbon capture and adds to a push by the office to get money out the door before the election. A victory by former President Donald Trump could halt transactions and make the program essentially dormant like it was during the first Trump administration. 
What is your outlook on the ammonia space? Join the conversation below. 
Some analysts say certain deals could still get done if Trump wins because oil companies favor ammonia and carbon capture. An initiative involving a dozen fossil-fuel companies including Exxon and Chevron CVX 0.53%increase; green up pointing triangle is one of Wabash’s investors.  
“This is a bipartisan project,” Williams said. 
Write to Scott Patterson at scott.patterson@wsj.com and Amrith Ramkumar at amrith.ramkumar@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    U.S. Natural Gas Futures Post Second Straight Weekly Loss
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/u-s-natural-gas-gains-on-heating-demand-expectations-ea15d412
   </link>
   <content>
    1532 ET – U.S. natural gas futures fall for a second consecutive week amid low shoulder-season demand. “We can see a lot of sideways trading inside a very tight realm, and we’re just waiting for the weather,” says long-time natural gas trader John Woods. “There’s not a lot of demand, so you’re not going to see a lot of heavy volume, just people maintaining and a lot of day trading.” The U.S. election also adds some uncertainty, with “one person pro-drilling and another person not,” he adds. “For the next three weeks, we’re going sideways until we figure out who’s sitting in the White House and where we are with price-point and weather.” The Nymex front month settles down 1.6% at $2.632/mmBtu for a 7.8% weekly loss. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com) 
Advertisement 
0858 ET – U.S. natural gas futures are higher with weather forecasts adding some demand next week. While lost demand is expected from power outages caused by Hurricane Milton, on the bullish side balances remain tight with inventory surpluses expected to shrink further, NatGasWeather.com says in a note. Demand is expected to be light through the weekend but colder trends appear next week, with an early season cold shot tracking into the Midwest and Great Lakes, the forecaster adds. The Nymex front month is up 1.6% at $2.718/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    U.S. Natural Gas Futures Falls as Major Storm Nears Florida
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/u-s-natural-gas-futures-move-lower-as-storm-looms-24b63a6f
   </link>
   <content>
    1502 ET – U.S. natural gas futures lose ground with market attention on Hurricane Milton as it approaches the Florida coast. Possible causes for today’s losses are “weak cash prices, anticipated demand destruction from Hurricane Milton, ERCOT demand weakening and the potential for stronger U.S. production in time,” NatGasWeather.com says in a note. Tomorrow’s EIA inventory report is expected to show further shrinkage in the surplus, with an injection of 70 Bcf into storage, according to a Wall Street Journal survey of analysts. The Nymex front month settles down 2.7% at $2.660/mmmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com) 
Advertisement 
0926 ET – U.S. natural gas futures are lower with the market watching Hurricane Milton as it approaches Florida with the threat of devastation and power outages lowering demand for gas. Still, heating demand is expected to pick up over the next week to 10 days, and LNG exports are likely to increase as Cove Point LNG completes maintenance, Eli Rubin of EBW Analytics says in a note. “If support at $2.66/mmBtu can hold, a near-term rebound is probable,” he says. The Nymex front month is off 1.9% at $2.682/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Peak Oil Demand Isn’t on the Horizon, OPEC Says
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/business/energy-oil/peak-oil-demand-isnt-on-the-horizon-opec-says-e643ac82
   </link>
   <content>
    Global demand for oil is set to climb over the next two decades, with the fossil fuel expected to hold a nearly 30% share of the energy mix even as the world ramps up efforts to reduce emissions, the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries said. 
In its annual report on long-term energy trends, the cartel said oil demand is forecast to reach 120.1 million barrels a day in 2050 from 102.2 million barrels a day last year. Demand from non-OECD countries is projected to rise by 28 million barrels a day in the period, while OECD nations are expected to witness a 10% growth decline. 
“There is no peak oil demand on the horizon,” OPEC said. 
Rising consumption would be a boost for the group’s 12 members, whose income is heavily dependent on oil. The organization, which publishes closely-watched oil supply and demand forecasts, has been typically more optimistic than others about the continued use of oil. 
Earlier this year, the International Energy Agency—which represents a group of oil consumer countries including the U.S.—said global oil markets are headed toward a major glut this decade due to surging supplies and slowing demand, with oil demand growth set to peak by 2029. 
According to OPEC’s forecast, oil demand is estimated to reach 112.3 million barrels a day in 2029, a 10.1 million barrels a day increase compared with last year. Non-OECD oil demand is projected to rise by 9.6 million barrels a day between 2023 and 2029, reaching more than 66 million barrels a day, while OECD demand is expected to fall by 500,000 barrels a day. 
In order to meet demand growth, investment in the oil sector needs to be significant in the coming years, OPEC said, reaching an estimated total of $17.4 trillion between now and 2050, or around $640 billion per year on average. 
Oil and gas are expected to remain crucial for energy supply through the middle of the century, with their combined share in the energy mix expected to stay above 53%, according to OPEC. Oil is set to account for 29.3% of it, with the bulk of demand growth coming from the petrochemicals, road transport and aviation sectors. 
Tuesday’s report comes as oil prices have found short-term support from elevated tensions in the Middle East, new hurricane threats in the U.S. and a fresh round of fiscal measures in China. Brent crude, the international oil benchmark, was recently trading around $75 a barrel, while the U.S. oil gauge West Texas Intermediate was around $72 a barrel. 
Israel’s latest airstrikes on Iran-backed militant group Hezbollah in Lebanon have raised fears of a wider war that could seriously disrupt supply, while a major hurricane looms over the U.S. Gulf of Mexico, threatening production. Meanwhile, China injected fresh support for the economy on Tuesday, boosting the wider commodities complex as lackluster demand in the top crude importer has been a major drag on prices over the last few months. 
Still, oil prices are down around 4% on the month, capped by persistent concerns over Chinese consumption trends and the prospect of increased supplies from OPEC and its allies. 
Global demand for all forms of energy is set to expand by 24% in the period to 2050, reaching 374 million barrels of oil equivalent a day in 2050 from 301 million barrels of oil equivalent a day in 2023, OPEC said. Demand will be driven by developing countries, which are projected to see an increase of 73.5 million barrels of oil equivalent a day, with around 30% of non-OECD growth coming from India alone. 
The cartel said its forecast of global oil demand stems from its expectation of strong population and economic growth through the middle of the century. The cartel forecasts the global population will grow to 9.7 billion by 2050 from just over 8 billion currently, mainly driven by a substantial demographic surge in non-OECD regions. 
Global economic growth is also set to grow robustly, with an average annual increase of 2.9% a year between 2023 and 2050. Non-OECD countries are set to expand at an annual rate of 3.7%, while OECD nations are expected to experience a more modest annual growth of 1.6%. 
With the exception of coal, demand for all primary fuels is set to grow through 2050. The largest increase is expected to come from renewables—mainly wind and solar—followed by natural gas, while coal demand is forecast to fall due to stricter regulations. 
OPEC said the world still needs to ramp up efforts to reduce emissions, improve efficiencies, and introduce low-carbon solutions through investment in technology such as carbon capture and clean hydrogen. 
Yet, climate action shouldn’t come at the expense of global energy security, OPEC said. “While energy policy ambitions remain high, the outlook expects greater scrutiny and pushback on some overly ambitious policy targets.” 
OPEC said supply from countries not participating in the Declaration of Cooperation—the formal name for OPEC+—is projected to increase by 7.1 million barrels a day between 2023 and 2029, reaching 58.8 million barrels a day by the end of the decade. Supply growth is then expected to slow in the long-term, to 57.3 million barrels a day in 2050 from 51.7 million barrels a day in 2023. 
Supply from the OPEC+ alliance is, instead, projected to grow to 53.8 million barrels a day in 2029 from 50.3 million barrels a day last year, and reach 62.9 million barrels a day by 2050. According to the cartel, that means the group’s share in global liquids supply will rise to 52% in the middle of the century from 49% in 2023. 
Advertisement 
Write to Giulia Petroni at giulia.petroni@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    U.S. Natural Gas Futures Start Week Lower
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/u-s-natural-gas-futures-start-week-lower-60c43ae7
   </link>
   <content>
    Advertisement 
0857 ET – U.S. natural gas futures move lower as a pickup in production offsets added demand from the return of Cove Point LNG after maintenance, while October weather forecasts offer limited support. A cold snap this week into the Midwest and Northeast is expected to be countered by comfortable temperatures in Texas and the South, followed by a mild second half of the month. “This period remains solidly bearish as it’s simply not hot or cold enough,” NatGasWeather.com says in a note. The forecaster adds, however, that it expects more heating degree days to be added for the 6-15-day period that is currently implied. The Nymex front month is off 2.7% at $2.560/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    U.S. Natural Gas Futures Retreat From Resistance
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/u-s-natural-gas-futures-slip-with-storm-in-view-a4c7d110
   </link>
   <content>
    1504 ET – U.S. natural gas futures pull back further from the $3 level tested several times last week. The reversal is an indication the recent rally may have been overextended, says Andy Huenefeld of Pinebrook Energy Advisors in a note. “With $3.00 per mmBtu confirmed as important psychological resistance, that level will present the first major hurdle standing in the way of further upside in the coming weeks.” The market continues to weigh the decline in the storage surplus against sagging shoulder-season demand, he adds. “With heating load slowly beginning to bubble up, residential and commercial demand will become a more important driver of weekly storage changes.” Also on traders’ radars is Hurricane Milton, which is projected to hit Florida’s Gulf coast Wednesday as a major hurricane. The Nymex front month settles down 3.8% at $2.746/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com) 
Advertisement 
0859 ET – U.S. natural gas futures edge lower with the market watching Hurricane Milton that’s seen reaching Florida’s Gulf coast midweek as a major storm. “The storm’s trajectory may cause brief hiccups in LNG shipping routes, but is likely to remain clear of any threat to Gulf Coast LNG export infrastructure or Gulf of Mexico production,” Eli Rubin of EBW Analytics says in a note. With some power outages still lingering after Hurricane Helene, “risks of renewed power-sector gas burn losses across Florida may contribute to near-term Nymex gas consolidation,” he adds. The Nymex front month is off 1.2% at $2.821/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Last Year’s Warm Winter Likely Means Cheap Heat This Year
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/last-years-warm-winter-likely-means-cheap-heat-this-year-5575d1f0
   </link>
   <content>
    A persistent glut of natural gas is shaping up to be good news for Americans this winter, likely keeping heating bills down despite forecasts for colder weather. 
On average, the nearly 60 million American homes heated with natural gas should cost just a few more dollars to warm than last year, or $602, the Energy Information Administration estimated this week. 
Utility bills have been front and center for consumer sentiment since Russia’s 2022 invasion of Ukraine shocked global energy markets and sent prices surging. Meanwhile, air-conditioning bills have busted budgets during a string of broiling summers. Heating and cooling costs have become a significant political issue heading into next month’s presidential election.  
“We expect most households will spend similar amounts to last year,” said EIA Administrator Joe DeCarolis.  
Bills at homes heated electrically are forecast to be 2% higher for November through March, totaling $1,054 on average, which includes power used other than for heat.  
The cost of propane, used mainly in the rural North, and heating oil, burned mostly in the Northeast, are expected to be flat and slightly lower, respectively. 
The EIA expects this coming winter to be colder than last year, particularly in the Midwest, but not dramatically so. Specifically, it forecasts 5% more heating degree days this winter compared with last year, though 2% fewer than the 10-year average, DeCarolis said. 
Expert recommendations on products and services, independent from The Wall Street Journal newsroom. 
Heating-degree days are a population-weighted measure of temperatures below 65 degrees Fahrenheit that energy traders use to gauge demand. 
If winter is warmer than anticipated, heating expenses could even be less than last year, according to the EIA.  
That is mostly thanks to the oversupply of natural gas, which is piped into homes to fuel boilers and furnaces and burned to generate much of the country’s electricity. Last winter was the warmest on record in the U.S. and left a lot of fuel unburned. 
The glut pushed natural-gas prices to some of the lowest levels in decades and persisted through one of the hottest summers so far, during which power plants burned more gas than ever to keep air conditioners running. 
Bank of America analysts said the boom in renewable-energy production, particularly a 36% year-over-year increase in solar output, helped keep power prices in check and even more gas from being needed. 
“The availability of gas has helped moderate power prices across the U.S., coupled with a large ramp-up in renewables,” said Francisco Blanch, commodity strategist at Bank of America. 
Even after drillers idled rigs and curtailed output to buoy prices, there is still 5.1% more gas in domestic storage facilities than normal for this time of year, according to EIA data. Traders have a few weeks to stockpile gas before most of the country turns on the heat and inventories are drawn down. 
Natural-gas futures ended Thursday at $2.675 per million British thermal units, down 20% from a year earlier and 58% lower than two years ago. 
Analysts say they expect weak gas prices in the near term. Forecasts suggest that even though some parts of the country will get chilly in the coming weeks, this month is likely to be one of the warmest Octobers in years. 
Hurricanes are taking a toll on demand, too. Tens of thousands of customers remain without power after Hurricane Helene knocked out electricity for millions when it blasted across the Southeast late last month. Meanwhile, Hurricane Milton hit a heavily populated swath of Florida’s Gulf Coast overnight and cut off power for millions more. 
Natural-gas futures have shed 8.2% over the past week as traders have adjusted their math to account for a steep decline in demand in Florida, where about 75% of electricity is generated by burning gas. 
The big question in the market is when producers will restore curtailed production. A cold snap could prompt a quick response from producers, who have been drilling wells this year but waiting for higher prices to complete them and bring gas to market.  
“Storage inventories are still fairly high,” said Leticia Gonzales, managing director of North American natural-gas pricing at Natural Gas Intelligence. “There’s no need to really start to bring back production yet.” 
How are lower fuel prices having an effect on you? Join the conversation below. 
Write to Ryan Dezember at ryan.dezember@wsj.com 
Advertisement 
Coverage of investment in green energy, selected by the editors
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:07
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Natural Gas Lower as Weather Forecast Moderates
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/natural-gas-lower-as-weather-forecast-moderates-af18f74b
   </link>
   <content>
    Advertisement 
1025 ET – Natural gas futures are down 0.5% to $2.910 per million British thermal units, with forecasts for a cooler East Coast in the near-term. Also, traders are viewing the current outlook for tropical storms active in the Atlantic Ocean as having a lesser impact on the continental U.S. than previously forecast. “[The] current tropical storm in the Gulf of Mexico is being downgraded as it is expected to take partial landfall in the Yucatan,” BOK Financial BOKF -0.04%decrease; red down pointing triangle says in a note. The firm adds that natural gas futures may be nearing overbought after recent sessions, making a streak of selling possible in the near-term. (kirk.maltais@wsj.com; @kirkmaltais)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:08
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Ukraine’s Gas-Storage System Remains Fully Operational Despite Russian Attacks, Naftogaz CEO Says
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/business/ukraines-gas-storage-system-remains-fully-operational-despite-russian-attacks-naftogaz-ceo-says-4d2ca8f4
   </link>
   <content>
    Ukraine’s gas-storage facilities were a critical outlet for Europe last year and remain so despite Russian attacks, Naftogaz’s Chief Executive Officer Oleksiy Chernyshov said. 
This year, a sharp decline in gas injected by European traders into Ukraine’s underground storage facilities—the largest in the continent—is down to market dynamics, according to Chernyshov. Russian missile and drone strikes haven’t affected the country’s ability to store or withdraw gas for customers. 
Still, the volume of foreign gas into Ukraine storage so far this year has dropped to around 0.5 billion cubic meters from 2.5 billion cubic meters in 2023. Foreign customers have around 10 billion cubic meters of available storage capacity in the country. 
Chernyshov spoke about Naftogaz’s storage system and its role in European energy security. The following has been edited for length and clarity. 
Q: How much gas are European traders storing into Ukraine’s system? 
A: Naftogaz runs a very extensive gas storage system, with 31 billion cubic meters of capacity. Most of the biggest storage facilities are located in Western Ukraine, at the border with the European Union. In terms of Ukrainian consumption of gas and storage, we normally don’t need any more than half of the storage for our own needs. We are welcoming traders to store gas in our systems because that brings more business, and if the system receives more gas the pressure parameters are better. 
In 2022, we witnessed the greatest downturn, with European traders storing 0.31 billion cubic meters of gas in our system. In 2023 we were more successful and managed to get 2.5 bcm. This year, the spread isn’t so attractive for traders and, at the moment, the volume of gas stored in our system [by foreign customers] is around 0.5 bcm. The main motivation is the price spread, which this year isn’t so attractive. Given the transportation costs and storage costs, it might not work in the way it worked out last year. So that is the main motivation. 
Q: Are Russian attacks against your energy infrastructure playing a role? 
A: We obviously have continuous attacks. In March and April, we had several attacks on our storage system. Some of our equipment was significantly damaged, but those damages didn’t affect our operational capabilities. We passed international stress tests several times, and they confirmed the reliability of the system and our operational capability to withdraw volumes. Also, the storage is located up to three kilometers underground. 
Q: What conditions do you offer to foreign traders? 
A: Our pricing and our price proposal are very attractive. This year, we made changes to the gas storage code, which now allows booking guaranteed capacities, not for the storage year, but for any number of months within the storage year[…] I’m willing to offer more incentives in line with the gas code. 
Q: A deal allowing Russian gas to transit through Ukraine en route to Europe is set to expire at the end of the year. Is that going to have a significant impact on gas flows? 
A: The volumes transiting through Ukraine aren’t exceeding 14 bcm per year, which represents roughly 4% of overall European consumption, so this stream might not have a great impact on pricing, because the volume isn’t so big. Obviously, there are countries that are more dependent on that and we want them to still be energy secure. 
Q: What role does Ukrainian storage play for Europe? 
A: Ukrainian storage, because of its size, location and infrastructure, is part of the European gas storage system. I’m sure, once Ukraine is a member of the EU, and probably even sooner, we should agree on a closer collaboration. 
Ukraine might play a role as a strategic energy hub in the EU, and we are eager to do that. We have a very extensive transportation system that is capable of bringing more than 150 bcm of gas to Europe per year, and have extensive storage. All of that makes us a very important player in this market. 
Building up sufficient strategic gas reserves ahead of the winter is no longer a commercial matter. It is a matter of Europe’s energy and economic security. We have a vast gas storage system and transportation infrastructure, and we stand ready to serve as Europe’s energy security anchor. 
Advertisement 
Write to Giulia Petroni at giulia.petroni@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:08
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Kazatomprom Shares Soar as Uranium Excitement Spreads to Asia
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/kazatomprom-shares-soar-as-uranium-excitement-spreads-to-asia-27cbd28c
   </link>
   <content>
    Shares in Kazatomprom have surged this week after a trio of events increased investor focus on uranium, underlining improved market sentiment regarding nuclear energy. 
Shares in the world’s top uranium producer traded 9% higher at $38.98 in afternoon trading in Europe, paring the year-to-date loss to 7.7%. 
Commodity prices rallied Tuesday after China’s central bank unveiled a package of measures to energize its ailing economy. This drove shares in European mining companies markedly higher, with majors such as Glencore, Anglo American, Rio Tinto and Antofagasta dominating the FTSE 100-index in London. 
The China stimulus package followed Monday’s news that 14 major global banks and financial institutions pledged support to triple global nuclear energy capacity by 2050—a goal endorsed by 22 countries at the COP28 climate summit last December. 
On Friday, Constellation Energy and Microsoft said they plan to restart Pennsylvania’s Three Mile Island, the site of the worst nuclear power accident in the U.S., to help power the tech giant’s growing artificial intelligence ambitions. 
“The Constellation/Microsoft announcement on Friday clearly set things off, with a main focus on Western equities,” Per Jander, director of nuclear fuel and investor services at WMC, said. 
Shares in Cameco, Canada’s top producer and the second-largest producer globally, and other Western uranium equities reacted well on the news, with the Saskatonian company closing Friday up 8.1%. Kazakh state-owned Kazatomprom ended Friday 0.5% down. 
However, the China stimulus announcement seems to have spread the excitement to Asian equities, Jander said. 
“After several months of soft investor sentiment in the sector, the uranium market is shaking off macro-related noise and refocusing on the very strong industry fundamentals,” John Ciampaglia, chief executive of metals-investment manager Sprott Asset Management, said. 
For decades, nuclear energy was considered problematic by investors and regulators due to its spotted history of accidents, waste disposal concerns and construction delays. 
However, it has recently emerged as a twin solution to both energy security concerns and decarbonization ambitions. In January, prices hit a 16-year high on supply concerns following production cuts from both Kazatomprom and Cameco. 
“Generalist investors are starting to take notice of the important role of nuclear energy to meet the growing electricity demands from AI data centers, reshoring of manufacturing, EVs and defense industries,” Ciampaglia said. 
In a June note, UBS analysts said a combination of strong, coordinated government backing—like that seen in China and India—and the accelerated construction of AI and data centers could rapidly accelerate nuclear energy expansion. 
Near-term uranium near term prices were up 0.8% at $80.00 a pound on the New York Metal Exchange in afternoon trading in Europe. 
Advertisement 
Write to Christian Moess Laursen at christian.moess@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:08
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Hurricane Milton Looks to Derail Florida’s Fragile Orange Recovery
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/hurricane-milton-looks-to-derail-floridas-fragile-orange-recovery-7288f12c
   </link>
   <content>
    The Sunshine State’s ailing citrus industry is bracing for a haymaker in the form of a direct hit from Hurricane Milton. 
Florida’s orange groves, which have been in recovery mode since being rocked by Hurricane Ian in 2022, are in danger of seeing those gains reversed, as Hurricane Milton is predicted to bring triple-digit wind speeds when it makes landfall late Wednesday into early Thursday morning. The massive storm is expected to knock off fruit from the current crop and could cause damage to trees that will take years to replace. 
“This is one of the most challenging periods the industry has ever faced,” said Matt Joyner, head of Florida Citrus Mutual, which represents 1,500-2,000 citrus growers in the state. 
Florida’s beleaguered orange groves had been making a comeback from damage caused by persistent disease and a string of powerful hurricanes in recent years. For the 2023/24 marketing year, which ended July 31, the USDA said that total orange production was 17.96 million boxes. That’s up 14% from the previous year – although still less than half of where production was before Ian hit, which was already the lowest it’s been since 1945. 
The frequency of major storms landing in Florida has given growers little room to breathe – as farms are barely able to recover from the previous storm before getting hit with the next one. 
It’s hard to tell how far back Milton will set citrus for the 2024/25 marketing year, but farmers are preparing for the worst. Production out of Florida’s orange groves fell by roughly 60% following Hurricane Irma in 2017 and Ian in 2022, Joyner said. 
Milton is expected to make landfall in the heart of Florida’s citrus area, with four of the top five citrus-producing counties – Polk, DeSoto, Highlands and Hardee – in the direct path of the worst winds of the storm, as projected by the National Hurricane Center on Wednesday. 
The top five counties are where 71% of the state’s citrus production is concentrated, said the Department of Agriculture in an August report. 
Florida’s citrus production has also been hampered by what is commonly known as citrus-greening disease over the past 15-20 years. The bacteria stunts tree growth and ruins the fruit on the trees. There is no known cure, but citrus growers have finally been able to enact treatments that, at minimum, slow the proliferation of the disease. 
But there is little citrus growers can do to protect their crops from a raging storm. “We cannot shield the trees from the wind,” said Joyner, speaking on Zoom from his home in Bartow, Fla., where he plans to ride out Milton. 
Hurricane season runs in the Atlantic from June to November, hitting a high point in September and October, coming at a vulnerable time in the orange growth cycle. Early harvesting begins this month – with farmers picking fruit and processing plants making orange juice from now until May. That means that storms this time of year tend to knock finished fruit off of trees, ruining them. 
Frozen orange juice futures, which trade on the Intercontinental Exchange, found an all-time record high of $5.06 a pound in late August. The run-up in the futures contract came after Category 5-strength Hurricane Beryl formed in late June – the strongest hurricane to ever form that early in the hurricane season. Oranges produced in Florida are mostly used for juice, while those grown in California are used more as table fruit. 
The futures contract is up 0.9% to $4.80 a pound Wednesday morning, with traders of the low-volume contract waiting for confirmation for how much damage the storm may do to Florida orange groves. Retail prices for orange juice have also set record highs this year, according to data from NielsenIQ, with its most recent assessment at $9.83 a gallon. 
“We’ll likely see a dramatic move higher as more details come out about the growing areas being severely damaged,” said Chicago-based commodities analyst Peter Mooses. 
Advertisement 
Write to Kirk Maltais at kirk.maltais@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:08
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    U.S. Natural Gas Shrugs Off Above-Estimate Storage Build
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/u-s-natural-gas-futures-lower-ahead-of-storage-data-ec9e2ae1
   </link>
   <content>
    1503 ET – Natural gas futures snap a four-session losing streak despite a bigger-than-expected 82 Bcf increase in inventories for last week and concerns of lost demand as Hurricane Milton knocked out power across central Florida. “The surplus continues to shrink, but the rate of decline has slowed,” Mizuho’s Robert Yawger says in a note. “With four to six more storage builds left in injection season, it is unlikely that the surplus to last year will be sopped up heading into withdrawal season.” Storage last week was 176 Bcf or 5.1% above the five-year average, the EIA reported. The Nymex front month settles up 0.6% at $2.675/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com) 
1100 ET – U.S. natural gas inventories increased more than expected last week while still reducing slightly the surplus over the 5-year average. Gas in underground storage rose by 82 billion cubic feet to 3,629 Bcf, which was 5.1% or 176 Bcf above the 5-year average for the week, the EIA reports. The surplus fell from 190 Bcf the week before. Analysts in a Wall Street Journal survey had predicted on average an injection of 70 Bcf. After an initial dip to $2.588/mmBtu, Nymex futures pick up and are off 1% at $2.633/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com) 
Advertisement 
0909 ET – U.S. natural gas futures are lower for a fifth straight session with the market attentive to weekly inventory data and demand prospects after Hurricane Milton knocked out power for millions in Florida. The EIA is expected to report a 70 Bcf injection into storage for last week, according to a Wall Street Journal survey of analysts, less than the 5-year average injection for the week of 96 Bcf, further reducing the surplus. “Traders of both the speculative and hedge varieties are seeing little reason to approach the long side given the typical low-demand shoulder period and the impact of hurricane Milton where all indications are tilting toward widespread and extended power outages that could easily overwhelm any disrupted production within the Gulf of Mexico,” Ritterbusch says in a note. Front month Nymex natural gas is down 1.6% at $2.617/mmBtu. (anthony.harrup@wsj.com)
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 13:31:08
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Oil Price Expected to Weaken If OPEC+ Hikes Supply
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/business/energy-oil/oil-price-expected-to-weaken-if-opec-hikes-supply-3686bcf1
   </link>
   <content>
    Prospects of additional oil supply hitting the market if OPEC+ sticks to its output plans are raising fears of a market surplus, painting a rather grim outlook for crude prices. 
The international benchmark Brent crude and the U.S. oil gauge West Texas Intermediate are down more than 4% this week and almost 10% on the month, as fears of a global demand slowdown continue to dampen sentiment. 
The number of short positions held by money managers in Brent futures in the last two weeks has exceeded the number of longs for the first time on record, according to market experts. 
“Sentiment in the market is already weak, with a bearish macro narrative weighing heavily to the downside, and investors are currently far more responsive to bearish price drivers than to bullish ones,” BMI analysts said in a research note. 
Now, expectations that the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries and its allies will start unwinding voluntary output curbs of 2.2 million barrels a day starting from December is adding to market nervousness. Brent currently trades at around $71 a barrel, while WTI is around $68 a barrel, even as conflict in the Middle East escalates. 
OPEC+ had agreed in June on a road map to gradually restore previously halted supplies starting from October, but then steep price losses in September prompted the group to postpone its plans by two months. According to market watchers, its decision was based on two factors: falling interest rates, which are materializing, and recovering demand, which instead hasn’t occurred. 
If implemented, the output hike plan would bring back 180,000 barrels per day into the market each month from December 2024 to November 2025. 
Meanwhile, the Financial Times reported Thursday that Saudi Arabia—the world’s top crude exporter and de-facto leader of OPEC—is ready to abandon its unofficial oil price target of $100 a barrel as it prepares to increase output. Oil prices fell more than 3% on the news. 
According to analysts, such a prospect is set to weigh on prices in the short term, fuelling the idea that the Kingdom is no longer willing to give up market share and has sufficient alternative financing options to face a period of lower prices. 
“In the mid-2010s, when OPEC targeted market share to push out high-cost oil shale producers in the U.S., the oil price collapsed to $30 a barrel,” ANZ Research’s strategists Daniel Hynes and Soni Kumari said in a report. 
ANZ forecasts Brent crude at $65 a barrel in December and at $80-$82 a barrel in the second half of next year to reflect the phase out of OPEC+ cuts. 
“Any sustainability in oil prices will be contingent on OPEC refraining from entering an all-out war on market share. We don’t expect Saudi Arabia will embark on another market flooding strategy, but the market will remain nervous until it explicitly rules it out,” the analysts said. 
A price drop in the $30-a-barrel region is possible, but still represents a very pessimistic scenario, according to FxPro’s Alex Kuptsikevich. “Technically, the Brent price is testing support near $70,” the senior market analysts said. 
BMI maintains its Brent forecast of $81 a barrel for this year and $78 a barrel for the next, but said “the balance of risk to the outlook lies to the downside.” Analysts at Bernstein instead said that, assuming OPEC+ brings back 2.2 million barrels a day starting in December, an oversupplied market and rising inventories could drive Brent down to a low of $55 a barrel, averaging around $60 a barrel in 2025. 
Next week, OPEC+’s Joint Ministerial Monitoring Committee is set to take place. The committee has no decision-making power as its role is confined to making policy recommendations for the OPEC+ ministerial meeting, which is expected to take place in December. 
According to Commerbank Research’s Barbara Lambrecht, the JMMC will likely emphasize again that the implementation of the planned production hike depends on market conditions, and call for compliance with production targets and the implementation of compensatory cuts. 
Advertisement 
Write to Giulia Petroni at giulia.petroni@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-14 14:25:48
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
