<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
 <channel>
  <title>
   Title
  </title>
  <link>
   https://your-website.com
  </link>
  <description>
   Your feed description
  </description>
  <language>
   en-us
  </language>
  <item>
   <title>
    Oil Price Expected to Weaken If OPEC+ Hikes Supply
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/finance/commodities-futures/europes-gas-prices-rise-on-supply-concerns-7be80d0b
   </link>
   <content>
    Prospects of additional oil supply hitting the market if OPEC+ sticks to its output plans are raising fears of a market surplus, painting a rather grim outlook for crude prices. 
The international benchmark Brent crude and the U.S. oil gauge West Texas Intermediate are down more than 4% this week and almost 10% on the month, as fears of a global demand slowdown continue to dampen sentiment. 
The number of short positions held by money managers in Brent futures in the last two weeks has exceeded the number of longs for the first time on record, according to market experts. 
“Sentiment in the market is already weak, with a bearish macro narrative weighing heavily to the downside, and investors are currently far more responsive to bearish price drivers than to bullish ones,” BMI analysts said in a research note. 
Now, expectations that the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries and its allies will start unwinding voluntary output curbs of 2.2 million barrels a day starting from December is adding to market nervousness. Brent currently trades at around $71 a barrel, while WTI is around $68 a barrel, even as conflict in the Middle East escalates. 
OPEC+ had agreed in June on a road map to gradually restore previously halted supplies starting from October, but then steep price losses in September prompted the group to postpone its plans by two months. According to market watchers, its decision was based on two factors: falling interest rates, which are materializing, and recovering demand, which instead hasn’t occurred. 
If implemented, the output hike plan would bring back 180,000 barrels per day into the market each month from December 2024 to November 2025. 
Meanwhile, the Financial Times reported Thursday that Saudi Arabia—the world’s top crude exporter and de-facto leader of OPEC—is ready to abandon its unofficial oil price target of $100 a barrel as it prepares to increase output. Oil prices fell more than 3% on the news. 
According to analysts, such a prospect is set to weigh on prices in the short term, fuelling the idea that the Kingdom is no longer willing to give up market share and has sufficient alternative financing options to face a period of lower prices. 
“In the mid-2010s, when OPEC targeted market share to push out high-cost oil shale producers in the U.S., the oil price collapsed to $30 a barrel,” ANZ Research’s strategists Daniel Hynes and Soni Kumari said in a report. 
ANZ forecasts Brent crude at $65 a barrel in December and at $80-$82 a barrel in the second half of next year to reflect the phase out of OPEC+ cuts. 
“Any sustainability in oil prices will be contingent on OPEC refraining from entering an all-out war on market share. We don’t expect Saudi Arabia will embark on another market flooding strategy, but the market will remain nervous until it explicitly rules it out,” the analysts said. 
A price drop in the $30-a-barrel region is possible, but still represents a very pessimistic scenario, according to FxPro’s Alex Kuptsikevich. “Technically, the Brent price is testing support near $70,” the senior market analysts said. 
BMI maintains its Brent forecast of $81 a barrel for this year and $78 a barrel for the next, but said “the balance of risk to the outlook lies to the downside.” Analysts at Bernstein instead said that, assuming OPEC+ brings back 2.2 million barrels a day starting in December, an oversupplied market and rising inventories could drive Brent down to a low of $55 a barrel, averaging around $60 a barrel in 2025. 
Next week, OPEC+’s Joint Ministerial Monitoring Committee is set to take place. The committee has no decision-making power as its role is confined to making policy recommendations for the OPEC+ ministerial meeting, which is expected to take place in December. 
According to Commerbank Research’s Barbara Lambrecht, the JMMC will likely emphasize again that the implementation of the planned production hike depends on market conditions, and call for compliance with production targets and the implementation of compensatory cuts. 
Advertisement 
Write to Giulia Petroni at giulia.petroni@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-09 16:10:54
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
  <item>
   <title>
    Oil Price Expected to Weaken If OPEC+ Hikes Supply
   </title>
   <link>
    https://www.wsj.com/business/energy-oil/oil-price-expected-to-weaken-if-opec-hikes-supply-3686bcf1
   </link>
   <content>
    Prospects of additional oil supply hitting the market if OPEC+ sticks to its output plans are raising fears of a market surplus, painting a rather grim outlook for crude prices. 
The international benchmark Brent crude and the U.S. oil gauge West Texas Intermediate are down more than 4% this week and almost 10% on the month, as fears of a global demand slowdown continue to dampen sentiment. 
The number of short positions held by money managers in Brent futures in the last two weeks has exceeded the number of longs for the first time on record, according to market experts. 
“Sentiment in the market is already weak, with a bearish macro narrative weighing heavily to the downside, and investors are currently far more responsive to bearish price drivers than to bullish ones,” BMI analysts said in a research note. 
Now, expectations that the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries and its allies will start unwinding voluntary output curbs of 2.2 million barrels a day starting from December is adding to market nervousness. Brent currently trades at around $71 a barrel, while WTI is around $68 a barrel, even as conflict in the Middle East escalates. 
OPEC+ had agreed in June on a road map to gradually restore previously halted supplies starting from October, but then steep price losses in September prompted the group to postpone its plans by two months. According to market watchers, its decision was based on two factors: falling interest rates, which are materializing, and recovering demand, which instead hasn’t occurred. 
If implemented, the output hike plan would bring back 180,000 barrels per day into the market each month from December 2024 to November 2025. 
Meanwhile, the Financial Times reported Thursday that Saudi Arabia—the world’s top crude exporter and de-facto leader of OPEC—is ready to abandon its unofficial oil price target of $100 a barrel as it prepares to increase output. Oil prices fell more than 3% on the news. 
According to analysts, such a prospect is set to weigh on prices in the short term, fuelling the idea that the Kingdom is no longer willing to give up market share and has sufficient alternative financing options to face a period of lower prices. 
“In the mid-2010s, when OPEC targeted market share to push out high-cost oil shale producers in the U.S., the oil price collapsed to $30 a barrel,” ANZ Research’s strategists Daniel Hynes and Soni Kumari said in a report. 
ANZ forecasts Brent crude at $65 a barrel in December and at $80-$82 a barrel in the second half of next year to reflect the phase out of OPEC+ cuts. 
“Any sustainability in oil prices will be contingent on OPEC refraining from entering an all-out war on market share. We don’t expect Saudi Arabia will embark on another market flooding strategy, but the market will remain nervous until it explicitly rules it out,” the analysts said. 
A price drop in the $30-a-barrel region is possible, but still represents a very pessimistic scenario, according to FxPro’s Alex Kuptsikevich. “Technically, the Brent price is testing support near $70,” the senior market analysts said. 
BMI maintains its Brent forecast of $81 a barrel for this year and $78 a barrel for the next, but said “the balance of risk to the outlook lies to the downside.” Analysts at Bernstein instead said that, assuming OPEC+ brings back 2.2 million barrels a day starting in December, an oversupplied market and rising inventories could drive Brent down to a low of $55 a barrel, averaging around $60 a barrel in 2025. 
Next week, OPEC+’s Joint Ministerial Monitoring Committee is set to take place. The committee has no decision-making power as its role is confined to making policy recommendations for the OPEC+ ministerial meeting, which is expected to take place in December. 
According to Commerbank Research’s Barbara Lambrecht, the JMMC will likely emphasize again that the implementation of the planned production hike depends on market conditions, and call for compliance with production targets and the implementation of compensatory cuts. 
Advertisement 
Write to Giulia Petroni at giulia.petroni@wsj.com
   </content>
   <extractionDate>
    2024-10-09 16:10:54
   </extractionDate>
  </item>
 </channel>
</rss>
